## Marvin **Blake** Rochelle

4735 Cotswold Lane Birmingham, AL 35242 (256) 404-1521 blakerochelle@gmail.com

I am looking for a position in front end web design and user experience advocacy with a company that values creativity and innovation as well as an environment that will provide a permanent home that I can grow with. I have more than 15 years of experience in the technological services industry, including 15 years in all facets of web development, from personally meeting with clients to discuss goals for their application, to research and analysis, design, development, testing, and implementation of code and applications, as well as a variety of graphic design and artwork when needed. I also regularly perform additional tasks including testing, technical support, project coordination and publishing. Over time, I have developed sustained relationships with internal management, employees and customers based on knowledge and trust.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Tools and Skills:** Sketch, Adobe Illustrator & XD, MyBalsamiq, Foundation, Bootstrap, PatternLab, Responsive design, Atomic design, User-centered design, Agile and Lean development

**Languages:** HTML5, Sass, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery with a working knowledge of AngularJS and Java.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Infinity Insurance Company Birmingham, AL

2010 - Present

Auto insurance provider.

Senior Software Engineer - UI/UX Specialist

- User experience, user interface & interaction design along with front-end design and development for consumer facing and internal web applications using HTML5, Sass, Responsive Design, JavaScript, PHP, ¡Query.
- Promote and ensure consistent look, feel and experience across multiple Infinity domains and platforms.
- Define user experience concepts, provide design layouts, workflows, prototypes and graphics using tools such as: Sketch, Adobe Illustrator and XD, InVision and MyBalsamiq.
- Create and maintain libraries of reusable web components using Pattern-Lab, HTML, Sass, JavaScript and jQuery; to be reviewed and approved by marketing + business stakeholders and consumed by product development.
- Develop and facilitate UX workshops to help identify and define interaction and usability requirements in order to provide optimum user experience.
- Currently fill the designer role on a balanced team, where I help lead ideation, technical design and the launch of innovative MVPs. I help establish a shared vision across the company by building consensus on priorities leading to product execution. I work directly with business leaders, stakeholders and users to develop strategies which improve the performance, usability and effectiveness of applications while ensuring that users are considered at every phase of the product development process. Communicate both independently and collaboratively with the business, users, relevant industry groups and project teams to bring a holistic, innovative and user-centric design discipline to the development of solutions. Analyze products/projects needs at various stages and ensure relevant user research activities are performed (i.e. research/test protocols, questionnaires, user profiling, analytics, usability testing, etc.) in order to mitigate any associated risks.

**Red Mountain Technologies** Birmingham, AL Information bureau for the automotive and insurance industries.

2003 - 2010

### Lead Web Developer

- Utilize user-centric principals, design, develop, deploy, and document Web based applications that benefit both our customers and internal users. Applications are developed using HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, STRUTS 2 and ASP.
- Maintain existing Web based applications to ensure their accuracy and currency as well as diagnose and troubleshoot any problems.
- Maintain proper documentation for many job functions, including preparatory information, detailed process instructions and day-to-day activity notes via company blog using Movable Type.
- Regularly perform technical support duties when needed. Support functions include customer interaction and training, troubleshooting and system monitoring with interaction via SSH and SQL Advantage.
- Served as project coordinator for the IT department which involved managing day-to-day project goals as well as long term goals for the technical staff.
- Plan and prepare the company newsletter for mail and online dissemination.

### AutoCheck Auctions Birmingham, AL

2002 - 2003

Vehicle history data provider to over 95% of the auction industry. Customer Service Representative

- Interacted one-on-one with customers to help serve their individual needs.
- Coordinated with management to strengthen the relationships with our customers.
- Analyzed various databases to check the accuracy of historical vehicle information.

### **EDUCATION**

**UX Certification** 

October 2016

Nielsen Norman Group

Major: Management Information Systems

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

De-

cember 2001

Auburn University, Auburn, AL

Major: Management Information Systems